<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brace Industries</title>
    <link>https://braceindustries.com/</link>
    <description>Thoughts on software, data, and building things</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:16:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://braceindustries.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

    
    <item>
      <title>The Bitter Lesson of Data Warehousing</title>
      <link>https://braceindustries.com/writing/the-bitter-lesson-of-data-warehousing/</link>
      <guid>https://braceindustries.com/writing/the-bitter-lesson-of-data-warehousing/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>On a late Friday afternoon a wise data modeler on my team said a line that I don’t think I’ll ever forget.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Guys, you are bending over backwards to fix things in your warehouse, when you really should be concerned that you’re paying claims for people who aren’t in your membership system.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The whole call the client team was going on and on how they need to explore all these different convoluted ways to preserve the “referential integrity” and get the best possible match rate of tagging members to medical claims. There might have even been a mention of SCD type 3. </p>
<p>I think my collague had enough and carried on saying:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I could have some dummy plan in your system, and have been getting free healthcare for years. Don’t you think that’s the problem you should be solving.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Later I was chatting with him and he mentioned this was the classic case of smart junior people trying to solve for the problem right in front of them. Which is why this is such a bitter lesson. No matter how well you design, model, and build your data warehouse, if the source systems you are working with are poorly designed there’s nothing you can do about having bad data.</p>
<p>The whole team was optimizing for having the highest match rate where the true insight should have been “We're paying $XXM in claims for people we have no idea if they are our members“.</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Brace Industries</title>
      <link>https://braceindustries.com/writing/welcome/</link>
      <guid>https://braceindustries.com/writing/welcome/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>This is a sample blog post to demonstrate the static site generator. You can write your content using <strong>Markdown</strong> syntax.</p>
<h2>Getting Started</h2>
<p>Here are some things you can do with Markdown:</p>
<ul>
<li>Create <strong>bold</strong> and <em>italic</em> text</li>
<li>Add <a href="https://example.com">links</a></li>
<li>Include images</li>
<li>Write code blocks</li>
</ul>
<h2>Code Examples</h2>
<p>Here's a Python code snippet:</p>
<pre class="codehilite"><code class="language-python">def hello_world():
    print(&quot;Hello from Brace Industries!&quot;)

hello_world()
</code></pre>

<h2>Blockquotes</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>"The best time to plant a tree was 20 years ago. The second best time is now."
— Chinese Proverb</p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Lists</h2>
<h3>Ordered List</h3>
<ol>
<li>First item</li>
<li>Second item</li>
<li>Third item</li>
</ol>
<h3>Unordered List</h3>
<ul>
<li>Coffee</li>
<li>Tea</li>
<li>Milk</li>
</ul>
<h2>Next Steps</h2>
<p>Edit this file at <code>content/posts/welcome.md</code> or create your own posts in the <code>content/posts/</code> directory. Use <code>content/drafts/</code> for work-in-progress posts.</p>
<p>Happy writing!</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Static Sites in 2025</title>
      <link>https://braceindustries.com/writing/building-static-sites/</link>
      <guid>https://braceindustries.com/writing/building-static-sites/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Static site generators have evolved significantly over the years. This post explores why they remain relevant and how to build one from scratch.</p>
<h2>Why Static Sites?</h2>
<p>Static sites offer several advantages:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Performance</strong>: No server-side processing means faster load times</li>
<li><strong>Security</strong>: Reduced attack surface with no database or server logic</li>
<li><strong>Simplicity</strong>: Easy to version control and deploy</li>
<li><strong>Cost</strong>: Can be hosted for free on platforms like GitHub Pages</li>
</ol>
<h2>The Core Components</h2>
<p>A basic static site generator needs:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Markdown Parser</strong>: Convert markdown to HTML</li>
<li><strong>Template Engine</strong>: Generate consistent page layouts</li>
<li><strong>Build System</strong>: Process content and output static files</li>
</ul>
<p>Here's a visual representation of the build flow:</p>
<p><img alt="Static Site Generator Flow Diagram" src="/static/images/sample-diagram.svg" /></p>
<h2>Our Implementation</h2>
<p>This site uses:
- Python for the build script
- Jinja2 for templating
- Markdown with YAML front-matter for content</p>
<pre class="codehilite"><code class="language-python"># Example: Loading a post
post = Post('content/posts/my-post.md')
print(post.title, post.date)
</code></pre>

<h2>Design Philosophy</h2>
<p>The design emphasizes:
- <strong>Minimalism</strong>: Clean, distraction-free reading experience
- <strong>Typography</strong>: Readable serif fonts for body text
- <strong>Color</strong>: Warm, inviting palette inspired by natural tones</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Building your own static site generator is a rewarding exercise. It gives you complete control over your content and workflow while keeping things simple.</p>
<p>Try it out and make it your own!</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>